《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
刚刚来了位可信度极高的证人
A very credible witness has just come forward
他愿意出庭作证
and he's willing to testify.
你所有关于这项阴谋的供词他都愿意帮你作证
He'll corroborate everything you've said about this conspiracy.
是谁?
Who?
金先生  你对索娜了解多少?
How much do you know about Sona,Mr. Kim?
我只知道要干掉她
Only what I've been given clearance on.
我们已经转变了策略
There's been a,uh,change in strategy.
我还要为你们做多少事?
How much further would I have to go?
你只需要去趟巴拿马
For this,you only have to go to Panama.
没想到你也来这儿了 迈克尔
I didn't know you were gonna be here,Michael.
你在网上发消息给我说帝博格在这里
You e-mailed me.You said T-Bag was here.It's on the Web site.
我从没在网上发过消息
I didn't write anything on no Web site.
这里越看越象个圈套
This is looking more and more like a setup.
玛丽克鲁兹被他关在某个地方
He's got Maricruz locked away somewhere.
你要帮他找到那包钱
You're gonna help him get the money
要不然她就死定了
or she's dead.
站住  巴格威尔!
Freeze,Bagwell!
是西奥多 巴格威尔 是他杀了里面那个女人
Theodore Bagwell he's the one you want for that dead chick in there.
苏克雷  我们必须齐心协力
Sucre,you'd better pull it together.
快去追钱  拜托了
Go get the money,please.
你吓唬谁呢?
Who are you fooling?
你不会杀我的  亲爱的迈克尔先生
You ain't going to kill me,Mr. Michelangelo.
你下不了手的
You ain't got it in you.
林肯?
Linc?
- 你好  迈克尔- 你想干什么  亚历克斯?
-Hello,Michael.-What do you want,Alex?
把钱拿来  船留下
Bring me the money,bring me the boat.
你疯了
You are out of your mind.
我们都有对方想要的东西
We both have something the other person needs.
你这一切计划就为了救你哥
Your brother for your plan.
给你5分钟  好好考虑一下
Five minutes.That's all you have.
我没杀那个人  迈克尔
I didn't kill that man,Michael.
我要带你离开这里
I'm getting you out of here.
我只有三个星期了
I've got three weeks.
只要我们留有信念
Just have a little faith.
我已经尽力了
I did everything I could.
我知道
I know you did.
先生?
Sir?
要口香糖吗?
Chicle?
不需要
No.
汽水呢?
Soda?
那啤酒要吗  朋友?
Beer,my friend?
来点兴奋剂?
Spleef? Magic mushrooms?
提神醒脑  超级爽快
Burst your brains,split it wide open.
先生  尽管放心我很可靠
I'm your man,man.
这盒子里东西能带给你梦幻之旅
Magic Mystery Tour right here in this box.
如果我这里没有 我可以帮你去其他地方拿
And if I don't got it,I can get it.
走开
Beat it.
想好该怎么做了吗?
So you gonna do the right thing?
为谁做  亚历克斯?
Right for who,Alex?
你输了  迈克尔
You lost,Michael.
这就是你要的结果
That's what you've done here.
你会失去很多东西
And you're gonna lose a whole lot more,
除非此时此刻你跟我说
unless you tell me right here and right now
你会把钱给我
you're gonna bring me the money,
会把船留下
you're gonna bring me the boat.
然后放了我哥哥?
And you'll just let my brother go?
对
Yeah.
就像你对付特维纳
Just like you let Tweener go.
阿布鲁奇...
and Abruzzi...
还有赫威尔那招一样?
and Haywire.
事态不同了
Things are different now.
是吗?
Really?
对  我拼死拼活为他们效力
Yeah. The people I was working for,
他们...他们却出卖我
they kind of, uh...sold me down the river.
我现在只想远走高飞
Now I just want to go out to sea.
那真是太有趣了 我会记住这句话的
Well, that's funny--I'll have to remember that one.
我面临的牢狱之灾比你严重多了
I face more prison time than you.
在我们共同的敌人名单里 我比你还要多几个
I sort of jumped ahead of you a few spots on the public enemy list.
迈克尔  你是我拾回自由的关键  我与你也一样
You're my way to freedom,Michael, and I'm yours.
我们都了解对方有多少能耐  快决定吧
We both know what the other one's capable of. Come on.
让我们坦诚相见
Let's treat each other with a little respect here.
不耍花招  什么都没有
No games. No nothing.
就是两个人相互扶持
Just two guys doing each other a favor.
觉得如何?
What do you say?
你在哪?
Where are you?
米拉弗罗尔斯海运码头就在巴拿马城的郊区
Miraflores shipping docks,just outside of Panama City.
一个海上的大仓库
It's a big warehouse right on the water.
那太远了
That's a long ways.
我起码得花24小时才能到那
It'll take me at least 24 hours to get there.
那我自己过来
Well, then, I'd get moving.
亡命天涯的滋味如何?
How's it feel being on the run?
我会幸免于难的
I'll survive.
如果被抓就完了
Not if they catch you.
他们会让你坐电椅
They'll send you to the chair.
你觉得这是讽刺吗?
You think that's ironic?
应该是正义
Think it'd be justice.
金先生  我是亚历克斯 马宏
Mr. Kim, Alex Mahone.
尽快回电
Call me.
会有正义的
justice will be served.
今天我在这里透露的一切
What I'm about　to divulge to you
都将可能令我遭受杀生之祸
will in all likelihood　get me killed.
其实我可以肯定这一点
Actually, I guarantee it.
那为什么还要来?
Then why are you doing it?
因为这样做貌似为国效力
Because this was supposed　to be about country,
代表忠诚
about loyalty,
彰显正义 但事实上并不是
about what's right,but it wasn't
因为...
because...
我陷害了许多不该陷害的人
I wronged people　who should not have　been wronged.
命令都是由凯洛琳 莱纳斯下发的
Those orders were given　by Caroline Reynolds,
就是曾经的副总统
who was Vice President　at the time.
根据指示  我伪造证据...
Acting on those orders,I planted evidence...
获取尸体
I procured a body,
然后引诱林肯 布伦斯
I lured Lincoln Burroughs
那晚来到那个停车场
into that parking garage　that evening
制造一场不一样的谋杀案
under the auspices　of a different hit.
从一开始  我们就在设计陷害他
From the ground up,we framed him.
完美
Perfect.
然后林肯 布伦斯被判死刑
So, Lincoln Burroughs　gets executed,
人们开始遗忘特伦斯 斯蒂德曼
people forget　about Terrence Steadman,
遗忘了对他的评论  还有他的职务
the controversy surrounded him　and the presidency.
也没有人知道任何关于...公司的事
And nobody ever knows about...The Company.
是的  就是一个阴暗的政治阴谋团体
yes, which is a shadowy　cabal of corporations
影响着国家里发生的一切事
that pretty much influenceeverything that happens　in this country.
但是我不明白你所说的一切
But I fail to see how any　of this is relevant
跟莎拉 唐克雷蒂协助他人越狱
to Sara Tancredi and the fact　that she aided and abetted,
逃避拘留有何关系...
that she jumped bail...
她这么做是担心自己的生命安全
She did so because she　feared for her life,
而且合情合理
which was appropriate,
因为我接到命令要杀了她
cause I had orders to kill her.
你还在卖仙丹吗?
Are you still　in the magic business?
卖到天长地久
Siempre.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
恰克
Chaco.
已经很明显了
It's all here.
克里曼所说的一切 都证实了文件上的内容
Everything Mr. Kellerman said　is corroborated　in these documents.
鉴于现在的证据
In light of this evidence
请问原告律师   你还要继续控告唐克雷蒂医生吗
my question, I guess, to you　is whether your time　and resources
are　best spent　in pursuing charges　against Dr. Tancredi.
不会  事务所决定立即撤消对她的所有控告
No. My office will drop　all charges,effective immediately.
但是法官大人  我想花时间和精力 起诉这个人  克里曼先生
But, Your Honor,I would like　in prosecuting this man,Mr. Kellerman.
警官
Officer.
我不知道该跟你说什么
I-I literally don't even know　what to say to you.
很高兴能认识你  莎拉
It was good knowing you, Sara.
喂?
Yeah?
现在在哪?
Where are we?
巴拿马  很惬意的城市
I'm in Panama. Nice place.
晴空万里  微风拂面
Good weather. Cool breeze.
我问你那对兄弟在哪?
Where are we with the brothers?
你在半道截住他们的时候
When you get them　where they need to be
我会亲自赶来证实
I want to come down there　for visual confirmation.
那我建议你乘飞机来
Then I suggest　you get on a plane,
因为当你到这的时候
because by the time　you get here,
我已经抓到斯科菲尔德和布伦斯了
I will have Scofield and　Burroughs where you want them.
然后一切都会结束
And then this　whole thing is over.
莎拉  是我
Sara, it's me.
我知道这有点奇怪...
It's a strange thing...
给一个永远收不到信息的人留言
leaving a message　for someone you know　is never gonna get it.
我只能做这种最坏的假设  所以...
I can only assume　the worst, so...
这会是我给你的最后一条留言
this will be the last message　I leave for you.
我只是想告诉你我成功了
I just wanted you to know　that I made it.
不过少了你  我很失望
But it's no good without you.
不管如何  还记得...
Anyway, you remember when I...
还记得我跟你说过...
remember when I told you　about those...
在芭雅的欢乐时光有50美分啤酒吗?
50-cent beers　in Baja at happy hour?
这里的啤酒比那更便宜
They're even cheaper down here.
如果奇迹出现  你听到这留言的话...
If by some miracle,you do get this...
我希望你能听得更真切些
I need you to listen close.
莎拉...
Sara...
莎拉  还是让我们陪你出去吧
Sara, I suggest　we get you out of here.
外面有大把的记者
It's going to be　a media circus outside.
还会来更多的  走吧
It'll only get bigger.Let's go.
好的
Sure.
今天在芝加哥法院对莎拉  唐克雷蒂医生 的审判中爆出猛料
Larger, unexpected fireworks　at the trial　of Dr. Sara Tancredi　in Chicago today.
新的证词暗示了
New testimony has implicated
前总统莱纳斯女士合谋...
that former President Reynolds　was complicit
在其哥哥特伦斯 斯蒂德曼 谋杀案中弄虚作假
in the falsification of...
正受全国通缉的 被陷害凶手林肯 布伦斯
Purported killer　Lincoln Burroughs　who has fled the country　on a nationwide manhunt
将会立即被撤消所有控诉
will be exonerated　of all charges　effective immediately.
我的天哪  布鲁斯 林肯自由了
Oh, my God, Bruce,Lincoln's a free man.
迈克尔留了个言
Michael left me a message.
我的天
Okay... my God.
他不知道这件事 还在准备逃亡
He doesn't know.He's still planning on running.
快接电话  迈克尔  快点
Uh... Come on, Michael,come on, come on.
我会介绍你们认识
Let me do　the introduction.
可以  不过要让我来具体谈
All right, but I'll　do the talking.
没问题
Si
没办法 我要赶去告诉他
Okay, I got　to go to him.
莎拉  那可在3000里之外啊?
What that, about　3,000 miles, Sara?
确实很远 所以我们现在速回酒店打点行装
It is. So we're going to　have to swing by my hotel
你只管送我到机场就好
and you're going to have　to get me to the airport,
布鲁斯  因为我一定得告诉他 再也不用亡命天涯了
because, Bruce, he's got to know　he doesn't have to run anymore.
他现在干的事情可能会令他丧命
What he's doing right now　is going to get him killed.
老板  事情终于搞定了
The stars are finally　aligning, sir.
马宏抓住了布伦斯
Mahone's got Burrows.
斯科菲尔德也快了
Scofield's on his way.
索娜呢?
SONA?
我会处理好的
I will make it happen.
我亲自去处理
I'm going down there myself.
只要"一"就行
JUST　ONE　IS　NEEDED.
呃  我想我们都清楚这个"一"什么意思
Uh, I assume we both know　which one that is.
搞定了我电话通知你
I will call you when I get down there.
我  我就是...
I just... I-I...
想让你们听清楚点
I want you to listen really close, okay?
亚历克斯  亚历克斯  慢点说
Alex, Alex, slow down.
好 没问题
Okay, okay.
我...我们曾经讨论过复婚的可能性
I... We talked about getting back together,
再努力尝试一次
about giving it another shot.
没错  我也说过或许能再回首
Yes, and I said that maybe we could.
亚历克斯?
Alex?
你看在哥伦比亚
What about Colombia?
卡塔赫纳(哥伦比亚一海港)怎么样?
Cartegena?
去那里?
Go there?
你可以用暑假去不是吗?
You got summer break coming up
坎姆也跟着一起来
don't you? Same with Cam.
可是可以  但是...
Yeah, but...
我现在离那里不远
I'm not far from there
我就在想何不借此良机
right now,and I was thinking
团聚一场享受天伦之乐?
that why not just stick around and have you guys come down?
你不是一直想去的吗?
You always wanted to go, didn't you?
回故乡看看?
Visit the homeland?
没错  但是你不愿去
Yes, but you didn't.
我现在很乐意
Yeah, but I do now.
我的意思是或许我们可以
Yeah. I mean, I suppose
聚首两周直到暑假结束
we can maybe do two weeks at the end of the summer...
那你是答应了 对吗?
Is that a yes?That's a yes, right?
是的  我答应你
Yes, yes...
快来吧  极品咖啡、黄金海滩 还有野生动物园等着坎姆
Come on, great coffee,great beaches,wildlife parks for Cam.
听着亚历克斯  或许这会行不通
Alex, look, it might not work out.
你要做好思想准备
You've got to be prepared for that, okay?
不可能再像过去那样
I... It can't be like it was before.
永远不会恢复到原先那样
It will never be like before.
我现在才知道什么对我更重要
I know what's important now.I know what matters.
或许能在网上聊
Well, I guess I could...I could look online.
我不知道  我要挂了
I don't know, I should go.
帕姆  无论怎样不要离开我
Just come be with me, Pam.
回到我身边吧
Be with me.
你现在什么担心都不用了
You've got nothing to worry about, okay?
我只嫁给你
It's you I'm marrying.
冈萨雷斯先生...
你在干吗
准备离开
那太荒谬了  你刚刚失血过多休克
流失了3品脱的血
相当于你体内30%的血啊
会导致肾衰竭、脑缺氧 甚至会害你丢了性命
请接美国大使馆
帮我接通吧 谢谢
美国领事馆  请说
U.S. Embassy operator.
我在找一个朋友
I'm looking for a friend.
一个失踪了的美国朋友
A missing American friend.
他可能在医院里
He could be in the hospital.
也可能在监狱里
Could be in jail.
叫什么名字?
What's the name?
贝利克...
Bellick...
布拉德利 贝利克
Brad Bellick.
我可以和律师通话或别的怎么样的吗?!
Hey! Hey, do I get to call my lawyer or what?!
你们这里怎么这么蛮不讲理?!
What are you savages down here?!
我得和我的律师通话
I get to call my lawyer or something.
操你奶奶个熊
Freakin' banana benders.
你们终于抓对人了  就是他
Finally. That's him.
就是这家伙杀了那女孩
That's the guy.He's the one who killed that girl.
干的漂亮
Good job, guys.
好棒
Bueno
现在可以放我出去了吧?
Aren't you going to release me now?
你这畜牲
You're busted.
我吗?
Am I?
钱在哪里?
Where's the money?
在小帅哥迈克那
Pretty boy's got it.
他在外面很潇洒
He's out there with a royal flush
而你却在这儿陪着个混球
and you're in here with a busted straight.
这看上去可不公平啊
你的手看上去没怎么长好
Your hand don't look much better.
说不定我留了一手呢
Maybe I got an ace up my sleeve.
难道你还知道我不了解的事情?
You know something I don't?
你还是好好养腿伤吧
You should rest your leg, boss.
德尔胡斯  近来可好？
恰克 有什么情况？
我帮你物色了个极有钱的家伙
这位不速之客是谁？
-别激动  我们来谈生意的 -滚出去
有人告诉我可以做个交易
I was told we could make a deal.
小子  你离家千里之外
You're a long way from home, boy.
这里没有什么交易可谈
Ain't no deal for you here.
你还没有听过我的交易筹码
You haven't heard what I have to offer.
向你这样的家伙
Guy looking like you do...
来这里...
coming here...
唯一能提供就是“抓人入狱”
the only think you're offering is jail time.
你这疯子居然带了个警察来
我可不是什么警察
I'm not a cop.
上网查查看
Check online.
输入"迈克尔  斯科菲尔德"
Type in "Michael Scofield."
那和我根本无关
That means nothing to me.
关系到10万美金
Could mean 100 grand.
查询超过30秒 就把你扔下运河喂鲶鱼
This takes longer than 30 seconds, you're in the canal.Bait... for the catfish.
嘿...
Hey...
找到他了
悬赏10万美元抓捕FBI通缉犯 迈克尔  斯科菲尔德
给我讲清楚  为何要让我逮你去领赏金
You just gave me a 100,000 reasons to turn you in.
那是真的
That's true.
我想我是要给你更多的钱 让你别抓我
I guess I'll just have to give you a few more not to.
你知道  我是无辜的
You know I'm innocent.
是么? 可能吧
Yeah? Probably.
- 但你不在乎这个 - 我什么都不管 只想找回原先的生活
- And yet you don't care.-I don't care about anything other than getting my life back, no.
你妻子知道你究竟是怎样一个人么?
Your wife know who you really are?
是的 你也知道
Yeah, you know how it is.
好人有时候迫于外界压力也会干坏事
Good men doing bad things because of circumstance.
如果我是你的话 我会给她回个电话
I'd call her back if I were you.
让她彻底忘了你这个人
Tell her to forget you were ever born.
哦 是吗 你会吗?
Oh, you would, would you?
别让你自己的毒瘤害了她们
Stop the cancer from your life spreading to theirs.
我的毒瘤
Cancer of my life.
要不是你和你那糗事
if it weren't for you and your life.
我也用不着求她来这种鬼地方见面
I wouldn't be begging her to meet me in this third world dump
这样是没有出路的
There's no way out of this.
对你 对我们任何人来说都是
For you or for any of us.
我有出路
For me there is.
你花了多少了?
How much of it have you spent?
十万...
100,000...
二十万
200,000.
当然了 在这里 相当于百多万了
Of course, down here, it'd be more like a million.
可以生活的简直像路易十四那样了
Be Louis XIV on a sum like that.
巴拿马太阳王
The Sun King of Panama.
恐怕你现在连太阳都要见不到了
You ain't gonna be seeing much sun now.
我不清楚
I don't know.
巴格威尔  你知道么 在所有人当中
You know, Bagwell,out of all the guys,
越狱的八人里面  我认为你是
all eight of 'em, you were the guy I was hoping would go down
最该被乱枪射死的人
in a blaze of gunfire.
那你何不给我来上一枪
Why don't you give me your best shot.
完成你的任务
Finish the job.
也许我会的
Maybe I will.
看你那贼笑
That Siamese cat smile
真想把你的嘴给撕开
just makes me want to open you up that much more.
不是贼笑
It's Cheshire.
是奸笑
Cheshire cat smile.
贝利克先生
Sir Bellick.
我自由了?
I'm free?
这是干什么?
What the hell's this?
嘿 等... 等一下
Hey, wait... wait a minute.
他呢?
What about him?
人是他杀的
He's the one that did it.
祝你好运（西班牙语）
Bueno suerte(spain)
"祝你好运"?
Bueno suerte
这什么意思啊?
what's that mean?
what does that mean?
－什么意思?  －祝你好运！
-what does that mean?-Good luck.
这条路是去雷拉卡达警局的吗？
对的
你要帮忙吗？
贝利克
Bellick.
贝利克!
贝利克  她在哪?!
Where is she, Bellick, huh?!
她在哪?!
Where is she?!
－玛丽克鲁兹在哪?! －你想知道她在哪
-Where's Maricruz?!-You want to know where she is,
就想办法把我弄出去!
find a way to get me out of this!
我要出去!
Get me out of here!
玛丽克鲁兹...
Maricruz...
巴拿马城 米拉弗罗尔斯海运码头
-迈克尔 那船真漂亮      -答应我
-Michael, that's a beautiful boat.-Just promise me
你拿去后把名字改一下
you'll change the name when you take it.
我想我妈妈不会喜欢你的
I don't think my mother would have approved of you.
等我把事办完会考虑的 过来
Consider it done.Come on.
给我解开
Uncuff me.
不 还不是时候
No, not yet.
难道你想食言?
So is this the part where you go back on your word?
手举起来 举起来
Hands up. Hands up.
不
No.
就现在来说
And as of now
他们想要你活着
they want you alive.
为何?
Why?
问的好
That's a good question.
有时间你自己去想吧
Figure it out someday on your own time.
钱在哪?
Where's the money?
-把他放开       -不行
-Cut him loose. -No.
算了吧  亚历克斯  你已经拿到船了
Come on, Alex,you already got the boat.
表现一点诚意吧
Show a little good faith.
钱
The money.
我要...
I want...
我到了  你在哪?
I'm here. Where are you?Yeah.
我在仓库里
I'm inside the warehouse.
我就到
I'll be right there.
要行动了
Here we go.
你会说英语吗?
You speak English?
好的 是 米拉弗罗尔斯码头
Good. Yes, yes.Miraflores Docks.
是的 那儿发生了谋杀
Yes, there's been a murder.
一个穿着考究的亚洲男人刚被打死
A well-dressed Asian man has just been shot
被两个美国人
by two Americans.
快来 是的  快来
Come.Yes, come.
你要杀了他然后陷害我们
So you kill him and frame us.
为什么
Why?
这样就没有人再会找我的麻烦了
So everyone will leave me alone.
那才是我想要的
'Cause that's all I want.
陷害你们并得到钱
That and the money.
亚历克斯  那是不可能的
It's not gonna happen, Alex.
让他走
Let him go.
让他走 把钱给我
Give me the money.Let him go.
把钱给我!
Give me the money!
我发现了
I'm done found.
不要害羞
Don't be shy.
他们全归你了
They're all yours.
你说带他们到我们想要的地方
You said you'd have them right where we wanted them.
这不是那个地方
This isn't right where we want them.
好吧...
Well...
现在要你来完成剩下的任务
that's your job now.
噢
Oh.
我到此为止了
This is as far as I go.
或者还有什么
Or is it something else?
我们都在这儿的另一个原因是
Another reason we're all here.
就像这样
Like that.
像被出卖
Like a double-cross.
是 就是这样
Yeah, just like that.
说再见
Say good-bye.
就像你想好的那样  亚历克斯?
Like minds think alike,eh, Alex?
等你坐下  你的四肢会被锁在
Once seated,your four-piece will be mounted
地板的固定栓上
to the floor mount.
押解过程中禁止和任何人说话
During transport,do not speak to either...
我知道条例
I know the drill.
进去
Get in.
我们还要多久？  30分钟？
So, what do we got,another 30 minutes?
是 大概那么长时间
Yeah, something like that.
- 你为什么不走高速公路? - 高峰时段
-Why didn't you take the freeway?-Rush hour.
该死
Aw, hell.
什么
What?
发动机灯亮了
The engine light just came on.
它刚在车辆调配场修理过
It just got serviced at motor pool.
好吧 我们最好停在路边确认一下
Yeah, we better pull over just to make sure.
好的 我去检查一下
All right, I'll check it out.
在法国保卫战中 敢于面对纳粹的刽子手
In the French Resistance it was considered a high honor
是莫大的荣誉
to face a Nazi firing squad;
我记得我告诉过你安静点
I thought I told you to be quiet.
做你该做的吧
Meant you did your job.
至高荣誉是当他们向你射击时 你依旧保持微笑
The highest honor was to smile when they shot you.
都等不及了吧?
Took you long enough.
嘎屯湖  东运河
Lake Gatun,Eastern Canal,
去卡塔赫纳  27.50元
approaches to Cartagena. $27.50
怎么过去?
What's that crossing take?
如果你一直乘船
if you're under full sail all the time.
要花两天的时间
Two days
希望你在这里玩的开心
Good time of you to be down here.
没有暴风雨  什么都没有
No storms, nothing.
最近经历的风雨够多了
Had enough storms recently.
享受一下吧  这是次美妙的航行
Enjoy it.It's a beautiful crossing.
我正是这样计划的
I plan to.
这里的这艘船
This boat here,
是谁的？
who's it belong to?
你的?
the yours?
我们接到举报
We got a call that
有人用这艘船进行非法运输
this boat was used in some illegal trafficking.
不是这艘船 老兄
It's the wrong boat, pal.
你可以检查下 但是  嘿 你不能...
You can check it if you want to, but...
朋友  这里是巴拿马
This is Panama, friend.
开始熟悉起这的法律吧
Get acquainted with the law, huh?
我...
I...
大约是两公斤可卡因
About two keys of cocaine.
是的 我坚决认为你需要学点法律
Yes, I definitely think you need to get acquainted.
铐上
Chico.
呃...我...
Oh... I...
走
Vamanos.
你觉得他们抓到他了吗？
You think they got him?
那是艘很特别的船
It's a pretty singular boat.
可以运很多的可卡因
That's a lot of coke to be carrying around.
如果你掌舵的话  伙计...
If you're at the helm, man...
恐怕会进监狱  至少十年
Be doing some serious time; ten years minimum.
是  你会的
Yeah, you would.
我们没了船
We lost the boat.
至少我们搞到了那个死人的钱
At least we got dead man's money.
我们的余生无忧了
It's out ticket to the rest of our lives,
减去我给韦斯特莫兰德女儿的那份
minus what I'm sending Westmoreland's daughter.
嘿
Hey.
你出现了
You showed up.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
这是我的哥哥
This is my brother.
走这边
This way.
我们离开这里  再也不回头了
So we get out of here,and we never look back.
再也不回了
We never look back.
我想谢谢你  迈克尔 谢谢你做的一切
I want to thank you,Michael, for everything.
别客气
You're welcome.
这是我用你给的钱能搞到的最好的船了
It's the best I could do with the money you gave me.
能派上用处
That'll work.
谢谢
Gracias.
她很漂亮
She's very pretty.
她会把我们带到想去的地方 不是吗？
She'll get us where we need to go, right?
我说的不是那船 先生
Not the boat, sir.
我收到你的消息了
So, I got your message.
感谢上帝  我找到你们了
Thank God, I found you guys.
是啊  感谢上帝
"Thank God" is right.
迈克尔  林肯自由了
Michael, Lincoln's free.
什么？
What?
新闻里铺天盖地都是这消息
it's all over the news.
保罗 克里曼
Paul Kellerman
站了出来
came forward
提供了所有的资料
and he had, he had everything documented
而且他供认了一切
and he made a full confession.
你没开玩笑吧？
Are you serious?
没有
Yeah.
供认一切？
Everything?
一切  他对所有的指控供认不讳
Everything, all charges.
这样说的话...
What, uh...? No more...
意味着你不用再逃了
That means you don't have to run anymore.
那迈克尔呢?
What about Michael?
我爸有个朋友正着手这事
a friend of my father's getting into it,
不过根据目前的情况 他很确信
but he's pretty confident that under the circumstances
没人会再为这事追究你的责任
nobody's going to pursue you on this.
我得找点喝的
I need a drink.
那我去看看有什么
I'll go see what I can find.
来
Here.
帮我解开这个
Help me out of this.
我们成功了林肯
We did it, Linc.
我们成功了
We did it.
是的
Yeah.
还没
No...
还差那么一点点
you almost did it.
你想要钱?
You want the money?!
这就是  拿去
Take the money. Take it.
你以为这是钱的问题吗?
You think this is about the money?
把500万当作零花钱?
Pocket change like five million?
那又为了什么?
Then what is it about?
我哥被赦免了
My brother's been exonerated.
总统下台了
The President stepped down.
我们不再威胁任何人 一切都结束了
We're not a threat anymore.It's over.
你跟我们完了
You may be done with us,
并不意味着我们跟你也完了
but that doesn't mean we're done with you.
警察就在路上
The police are on their way.
这事由我引起的
It started with me.
放我弟弟走
Let my brother go.
噢 太感人了
Oh, that's sweet.
真是太感人了
That's sweet.
可惜你再也听不到了
You don't hear that much anymore,
听不到这种兄弟间的忠诚
that sort of fidelity in families.
兄弟俩为了对方而逃到天涯海角
Two brothers that'll go to the ends of the earth for each other.
只可惜你们要有一个为此付出代价
Too bad only one of you survive.
不要
Don't!
赶快跑
We got to go.
如果你们不投降出来
My men are ordered to fire if you don't
我们就开枪了
come out of there with your hands first.
来
Come on, come on.
在巴拿马谋杀可不是闹着玩的
Murder is not something that we take lightly here on Panamanian soil.
所以快出来投降
So come on out of there
这样就不会有人伤亡
and there will be no more death.
迈克尔我杀了人
Michael, I took a man's life.
不要这么想
Don't think about that now.
你和我之间有个约定  记得么?
You and I have got a date,remember?
两杯柠檬汁  两杯啤酒
Two limes and a couple of beers,
没忘吧
don't forget that.
最后警告你们一次!
This is your last warning!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
我杀人了
I took a man's life.
我们要一起离开这儿
We're going to walk out of here together,
而且还要告诉他们到底发生了什么
and we'll tell them exactly what happened.
看看我  看着我
Look at me,look at me, look at me.
我们要去告诉他们到底发生了什么
Then we're going to tell them what happened.
好
Okay.
我们会把一切都解释清楚的
We'll explain everything.
我会尽力帮助你
And I'm going to do whatever I can to help you.
好吗?
Okay?
恩
Yeah.
现在把枪给我
Now give me the gun.
给
Here.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你  莎拉
I love you, too, Sarah.
- 好的   - 你还好吗?
-'Kay.-You all right?
我很好
All right.Yeah.
走吧
Come on.
不许动!
Don't move!
我会开枪的!
I'll shoot!
- 迈克尔 你干什么 - 都不准动!
-Michael, what are you doing?-Nobody moves!
都别动 别动
Nobody!
你曾经为我牺牲了一切
You sacrificed everything for me once.
- 站着别动 - 不  我不能让你这么做
-Don't move!-No, I can't let you do this.
迈克尔! 迈克尔!
Michael!Michael!
现在该对你说谢谢了
Now it's time to say thank you.
是我  是我啊!
It was me.It was me!
- 他是清白的!  - 人是我杀的!
He's done nothing wrong!I did it!
- 是我干的!  - 他是清白的!
-He's innocent!I did it!-I did it!He's innocent!
- 是我!  - 不 他什么都没做!
-It was me!-He's done nothing wrong!
求你了!  求你!
Please! Please!
是我!
I did it!It was me.
他什么都没做过  他没有...
He's done nothing wrong.He hasn't
他没有开枪  他没有伤害任何人  求你们了  迈克尔!
shot anybody, he hasn't hurt anybody, please. Michael!
迈克尔  告诉他们真相!
Michael, tell them the truth!
迈克尔!
Michael!
他什么都没有做过!
He's done nothing wrong!
你好
Hello?
嗨  是我
Hey, it's me.
看来有点不耐烦了
Ooh, getting impatient.
让我想起了我们的大学时代
Reminds me of when we were in college.
你买票了没?
Did you buy the tickets yet?
没  我还在找
No, I'm still looking.
不用了
Don't.
怎么了
What?
都忘了吧
Forget about them.
忘掉我曾活在这个世上
Forget I ever existed.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你会说英语么?
Do you speak English?
- 是  有什么需要帮助的吗? - 是的
-Yes, can I help you?-Yeah.
我在找一位女士  她叫莎拉 唐克雷蒂
I'm looking for a woman--Sarah Tancredi.
她被带到这儿录口供   然后被释放了
She was brought in to give her statement and then released.
她刚刚走
You just missed her.
莎拉!
Sarah!
我还以为你不来了呢
I thought you'd never show up.
好了  我什么时候可以离开这里?
Okay, uh, when am I getting out of here?
我也在考虑这个问题
That's the thing.
计划出现了"小波折"
There's been a hiccup.
"小波折"
A hiccup.
听着  你们把我给抓了
Look, you got me...
在墨西哥光明正大地把我给抓了
you got me fair and square in Mexico,
难道这还不够?
all right?
我已经按你的要求去做
I did what you wanted me to do.
现在该放我出去了吧 正如之前说好的那样
Now it's time to cut me loose just like we agreed.
我们之前可没说好你要被警察抓住
Getting caught wasn't part of the agreement.
我被抓是为了成就你的诱捕
I got caught running your setup,being your bait.
现在我把斯科菲尔德给引来了
Now I got you Scofield down here,
我已经按你的要求去做了
I got you what you wanted.
可你被抓了 巴格威尔
You got caught, Bagwell.
你去哪?
Hey, wh... where...where you going?!
Where you going?!
你要的我都给你做到了
I got you what you want!
那几个崽子我都给你引来了
I got them boys down here!
我都按你的要求去做了
I did what you told me to do!
你听到了没有?
Do you hear me?!
你要求的我都做到了
I did what you told me to do!
I did what you told me!
我们到了
This is as far as I go.
将军...
General...
我相信在这跟你说件事很安全
I trust this is a safe place to speak.
关于斯科菲尔德的
It's Scofield.
逮住他了
They got him.
斯科菲尔德回到了狱中
Scofield back in the penn.
老实说
Got to be honest,
这样不一定有用
didn't think we'd see it happen.
要知道  他还是会想办法逃出去
You know he's gonna break out.
那是他的天性
It's in his blood.
让他逃吧  这正是我们所期待的
That's exactly what we want him to do.